This is everything that people hate
about politics. Something happened this
weekend in British politics which I
think exemplifies everything that people
find off-putting and ugly about
contemporary politics and we need to
talk about it because I think this has
ramifications not only for this
particular circumstance but how people
relate to liberal democracies across the
world. Something that we already know is
massively in question. So this weekend,
Kier Dharma moved to defend his
leadership of the Labour Party and
position as Prime Minister of the United
Kingdom by blocking a key rival to the
throne from standing as a member of
parliament. Andy Bernham, who we'll talk
about a little bit more shortly, is
presently the mayor of Greater
Manchester and is seen by many as a
potential successor to Karma as prime
minister, particularly given how
unpopular Karma currently is. However,
Andy Burnham would need to be a member
of parliament in order to challenge him
and therefore there are some hoops to
jump through if he were ever to succeed
in deposing him. Now, if you are
watching and you're in the UK, there is
every chance you are kind of sick of
hearing about this already. We're now
two days later, I think, and it is still
filling up the kind of latest news,
breaking news feeds on various
newspapers websites. And if you're
watching from anywhere else in the
world, because I know we get a bunch of
international viewers, I think there's
every chance that this story feels
really prochial and very specific to the
UK. And yeah, I really do feel like it
has massive ramifications. It tells us
so much about how politics is being done
in the here and now. the way in which
party systems are currently working and
the way in which voters are having their
choices shaped for them in a way that I
don't only think is like unfair to
voters or whatever, but I do think
really risks breaking trust in the
entire system.